Guide to the Mazzarella AIVS Collection of Librettos MSS.383
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series XXXIV: Leoncavallo
  - La Reginetta delle Rose, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento Tip. E. Reggiani
- Series XXXV: Mancinelli
  - Isora di Provenza, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Librettist: Zanardini, A.
    Performance City and Venue: Bologna: Teatro Comunale
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1884
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento Musicale Tito di Gio. Ricordi
- Series XXXVI: Mascagni
  - Guglielmo Ratcliff, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Heine, Enrico
    Venue: Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1894-1895
  - Isabeau, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Casa Musicale Sonzogno
  - Isabeau (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Publication City: Milano
  - Isis, 1898 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Performance City and Venue: Rome: Teatro Constanzi
    Performance Season/Date: November 1898
  - L'amico Fritz, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Librettist: Suardon, P.
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Stabilimento della Societa Editrice Sonzogno
  - Le Maschere (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Il Piccolo Marat, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Librettist: Forzano, Giovacchino
    Performance Season/Date: 1921
  - Il Piccolo Marat, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Forzano, Giovacchio
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Musica Sonzogno
  - Zanetto, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Librettist: Targioni-Tozzetti, Giovanni; Menaschi, Guido
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1895-96
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Edoardo Songzogno
  - Zanetto, 1930 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Musicale Sonzogno
- Series XXXVII: Massenet
  - Cendrillon, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Librettist: Cain, Henri
    Performance City/Venue: Theatre National de L'Opera-Comique
    Performance Season/Date: May 1899
    Publication City: Paris
  - Herodiade, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Librettist: Milliet, Paul; Gremont, Henri
    Performance City and Venue: Paris: Palais-Royal, Galerie du Theatre-Francais
    Publication City and Publisher: Paris: Tresse
  - Le Jongleur de Notre-Dame, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Lena, Maurice
    Performance City and Venue: Paris: Au Menestrel
    Performance Date: 1905
  - Il re di Lahore, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Librettist: Gallet, Luigi
    Performance Date and Season: Quaresima 1878
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Tito di Gio Ricordi
  - Il re di Lahore, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: 1879
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Gio. Ricordi
- Series XXXVIII: Mercadante
  - Il Bravo, 1839 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Performance City and Venue: I.R. Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: La Quaresima 1839
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Gaspare Truffi
  - Il Bravo, 1840 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Performance Season/Date: Il Carnevale 1840
  - Il Briganti, 1836 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Librettist: Crescini, Jacobo
    Performance City and Venue: Paris
    Performance Season/Date: 1836
    Publication City and Publisher: Paris: Grange-Bateliere
  - Il Conte di Essex, 1833 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Performance Season/Date: Il Carnevale 1833
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Giacomo Pirola
  - Le due Illustri Rivali, 1839 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Performance Season/Date: Il Carnevale 1839
  - Elena da Feltre, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1843
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Gaspare Truffi
  - Emma d'Antiochia [1 of 2], 1835 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Baldassare, Cavallotti; Domenico, Menozzi
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: I.R. Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Il Carnevale 1835
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Luigi di Giacomo Pirola
  - Emma d'Antiochia [2 of 2], 1835 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gabriella di Vergy, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Performance City and Venue: Torino: Regio Teatro di Torino
    Publication City and Publisher: Torino: R. Teatro
  - Gabriella di Vergy, 1837 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Performance City and Venue: I.R. Teatro alla Canobbiana
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1837
  - Il Giuramento, 1837 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1837
  - Il Giuramento, 1838 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Performance City and Venue: Gran Teatro la Fenice
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale and Quadragesima 1838
    Publication City and Publisher: Venezia: Giuseppe Molinari
  - Il Giuramento, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Performance City and Venue: R. Teatro Alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1871
  - Leonora, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Performance City and Venue: Gran Teatro del Liceo
    Performance Season/Date: Agosto 1847
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: T. Gorchs
  - I Normanni a Paragi, 1832 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Performance City and Venue: I. E R. Teatro in via della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1832
    Publication City and Publisher: Lucca: Benedini and Rocchi
  - Orazj e Curiazj, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Performance City and Venue: I.R. Teatro alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1847
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Valentini E.C.
  - Il Reggente, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Ducale di Parma
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1844
    Publication City and Publisher: Parma: Carmignani
  - La Vestale, 1841 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1841
- Series XXXIX: Meyerbeer
  - Il Crociato in Egitto, 1832 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Riccardi
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1832
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: Mazzoleni
  - L'africana [1 of 2], undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Librettist: Scribe, Eugenio
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: G. Ricordi and co.
  - L'africana [2 of 2], undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - L'africana, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Scribe, Eugene
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Editice Libaria Modernissima "Floreal liberty" di Rossi Arturo
  - L'esule di Granata, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Performance City and Venue: I.R. Teatro alla Scalla
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima dell' anno 1822
    Publication City and Publisher: Minal: Giacomo Pirola
  - Les huguenots, 1910 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Il Profeta, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1883
  - Roberto el Diablo, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Performance Season/Date: Invierno 1851
    Publication City and Publisher: Barcelona: Tomas Gorchs
  - Roberto il Diavolo, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Performance Season/Date: 1865
- Series XL: Morlacchi
  - La Danaidi, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima 1819
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Giacomo Pirola
  - Giani di Parigi, 1818 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: I.R. Teatro alla Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1818
  - Tebaldo e Isolina, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Performance City and Venue: Reggio: Teatro Dell' Illustrissima Comunita
    Performance Season/Date: Maggio
    Publication City and Publisher: Reggio: G. Davolio, E. Figlio
- Series XLI: Muzio
  - Le due Regine, 1856 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Librettist: Peruzzini, Giovanni
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1856
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Paolo Ripamonti Carpano
  - La Sorrentina, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Performance City and Venue: Bologna: Teatro Comunitativo
    Performance Season/Date: November 1857
    Publication City and Publisher: Bologna: Belle Arti
- Series XLII: Nicolai
  - Il Proscritto, 1841 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series XLIII: Nini
  - La Marescialla d'Ancre, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Performance City and Venue: Padova: Teatro Nuovo
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera dal santo 1839
    Publication City and Publisher: Padova: Penada
- Series XLIV: Pacini
  - Bondelmonte, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Performance City and Venue: I. E. R. Teatro in via della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1845
    Publication City and Publisher: Firenze: Galletti
  - Bondelmonte, 1852 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1853
  - I Cavalieri di Valenza, 1828 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1828
  - Il Cid, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Librettist: de Lauziers, Achille
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1852
  - Ester d'Engaddi, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Librettist: Guidi, Francesco
    Performance City and Venue: Regio Teatro
    Publication City and Publisher: Torino: Fratelli Favale
  - La Falgname di Livonia, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Performance City and Venue: Barcelona: Teatro della Ecc.ma Citta
    Performance Season/Date: 1822
    Publication City and Publisher: Narcisa Dorca
  - La Fidanzata Corsa, 1842 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Performance City and Venue: Real Teatro S. Carlo
    Performance Season/Date: 1842
    Publication City and Publisher: Naples: Lautina
  - La Fidanzata Corsa, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro all Scala
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1845
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Truffi
  - L'Ebrea, 1844 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Librettist: Sacchero, Giacomo
  - L'Ultimo Giorno di Pompei, 1827 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    Librettist: Tottola, Andrea
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1827
  - Maria, Regina d'Inghilterra, 1843 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Librettist: Tarantini, L.
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1843
  - Niccolo dei Lapi, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Pacini, Giovanni
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Pagliano di Firenze
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1873
    Publication City and Publisher: Firenze: G. Polverini
  - Saffo, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro la Fenice in Venezia
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1869
    Publication City and Publisher: Naples: Ricordi
  - Saffo, 1875 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Performance Season/Date: 1875
    Publication City and Publisher: Genova: G. Schenone
  - Il Saltimbanco, 1859 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Librettist: Checchetelli, Guiseppe
  - La Vestale, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Librettist: Romanelli, Luigi
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1823
- Series XLV: Panizza
  - I Ciarlatani, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1839
- Series XLVI: Pasta
  - Atahualpa, 1875 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: A. Gattinoni
- Series XLVII: Persiani
  - Ines de Castro, 1837 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Series XLVIII: Petrella
  - Caterina Howard, 1866 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    Librettist: Cencetti, Giuseppe
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Apollo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1866
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: G. Olivieri al Corso
  - Il duca di Scilla, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Librettist: Peruzzini, Giovanni; Fortis, L.
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1858
  - Jone, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1857
  - I Promessi Sposi, 1869 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro di Lecco
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1869
  - I Promessi Sposi, 1883 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Series XLIX: Pfitzner
  - Palestrina, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Librettist: Pfitzner, Hans
    Publication City and Publisher: Berlin W.: Adolf Furstner
- Series L: Platania
  - Spartaco, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Performance City and Venue: Naples: Teatro San Carlo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1890
- Series LI: Ponchielli
  - Il Figliuol Prodigo, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Performance Season/Date: Stagione 1880
  - Il Figliuol Prodigo, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: G. Ricordi
  - I Lituani, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Ghislanzoni, A.
    Performance City and Venue: Roma: Teatro Apollo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1886
  - Marion Delorme [1 of 2], undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Librettist: Goliscianti, E.
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1884
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Gio. Ricordi
  - Marion Delorme [2 of 2], undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series LII: Puccini
  - Edgar, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1888
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Gio. Ricordi and Francesco Lucca
  - Edgar, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Gio. Ricordi and Co.
  - Le Villi, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Performance City and Venue: Torino: Teatro Regio
  - Il trittico (Il tabarro, Suor angelica, and Gianni schicchi), 1918 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    Librettist: Adami, Giussepe
    Performance City and Venue: New York: Metropolitan Opera House
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Recordi and Fred. Rullman, Inc.
- Series LIII: Refice
  - Cecilia (azione sacra), 1935 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Librettist: Mucci, Emidio
    Performance City and Venue: Roma: Teatro Reale Dell'opera
    Performance Season/Date: Febbraio 1934
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: G. Ricordi & C. Editori
- Series LIV: Ricci
  - Chiara di Rosembergh, 1841 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Performance City and Venue: Torino: Regio Teatro
    Publication City and Publisher: Torino: Tipografia Savojardo e Som
  - Corrado di Altamura, 1842 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Performance Season/Date: Fiera 1842
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: Dalla Stamperia Natali
  - Estella, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Librettist: Piave, Francesco Maria
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1846
    Publication City and Publisher: Milano: Tipografia Valentini E C.
- Series LV: Rossini
  - Armida [1 of 2], 1836 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    Librettist: Baldassarre, Cavallotti; Domenico, Menozzi
  - Armida [2 of 2], 1836 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, 1835 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1835
  - Il Barbiere di Siviglia, 1916 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Sterbini, Cesare
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: unknown
  - La Ceneretola, 1822 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Romano, Ferretti
    Performance City and Venue: Paris: Theatre Royal Italien
  - La Cenerentola, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    Librettist: Sevesi, Fabrizio
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Carignano
    Publication City and Publisher: Torino: Favale
  - La Cenerentola, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Librettist: Ferretti, Giacomo
    Performance Season/Date: Quadragesima 1835
    Publication City and Publisher: Venezia: Commercio
  - La Donna del Lago, 1848 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Librettist: Maggioni, Manfredo
    Performance City and Venue: Covent Garden Theatre
  - Elisabetta Regina d'Inghilferra, 1827 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    Librettist: Schmidt, Giovanni
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1827-28
  - La Gazza Ladra, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera dell' anno 1823
  - Ivanhoe, 1833 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro in via della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1833
    Publication City and Publisher: Firenze: nella stamperia Fantosini
  - L'Assedio di Corinto, 1834 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Librettist: Doca, F.
    Performance City and Venue: King's Theatre
    Performance Season/Date: June 1834
    Publication City and Publisher: Rupert Street, London: T. Brettell
  - L'Assedio di Corinto, 1842 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Librettist: Baldassare, Cavallotti
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1842-43
  - L'Inganno Felice, 1815 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Performance Season/Date: 1815
    Publication City and Publisher: Modena: per G. Vincenzi e Comp.
  - L'Iganno Felice, 1826 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Performance Season/Date: 1826
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: Ospizio Apostolice
  - L'Italiani in Algeri, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Le Comte Ore, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Scribe, Eugene; Delestre-Poirson, Charles-Gaspard
  - Mose, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Performance City and Venue: Bologna: Societa del Casino
    Performance Season/Date: 1829
    Publication City and Publisher: Bologna: Gassi
  - Mose, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Performance Season/Date: 1925
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: F. Madella and Sesto S. Giovanni
  - Mose in Egitto, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Librettist: Tottola, Andrea Leone
    Performance Season/Date: L'Estate 1822
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: dalla stamperia Mazzoleni
  - Otello, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Berio, Marchese
  - La Pletra del Paragone, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1822
  - Roberto Bruce, 1847 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    Librettist: Royer, Alfonso; Daez, Gustavo
    Performance Season/Date: 1847
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Giovanni Ricordi
  - Semiramide, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Performance City and Venue: London; New York: Royal Italian Opera; Academy of Music
  - Torvaldo e Dorliska, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
    Performance City and Venue: Bergamo: Teatro della Societa
    Publication City and Publisher: Bergamo: dalla stamperia Natali
  - Zelmira, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    Performance Season/Date: Quadragesima 1823
  - Zelmira, 1838 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1838
- Series LVI: Rubinstein
  - Neron, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Librettist: Barbier, Jules
    Publication City and Publisher: New York: Charles D. Koppel
- Series LVII: Salieri
  - Europa Riconosciuta, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Performance City and Venue: Milan: Nuovo Regio Ducal Teatro
    Performance Season/Date: D'Agosto 1778
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan
- Series LVIII: Solera
  - Il degonda, 1840 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima 1840
- Series LIX: Spontini
  - La vestale, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Librettist: de Jouy, Etienne
    Performance Season/Date: 1870-1871
- Series LX: Thomas
  - Mignon, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Performance City and Venue: New York: Oscar Hammerstein's English Opera Company
- Series LXI: Vaccai
  - Giovanna Gray, 1836 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1836
  - Saladine e Clotilde, 1828 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Series LXII: Verdi
  - Aida (volume 1), undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1871-72
  - Aida, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Editrice A. Cervieri
  - Aida, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Performance City and Venue: New York: The American Opera Company
  - Alzira [1 of 2] (volume 2), undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
    Performance City and Venue: Rome: Teatro Argentina
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1845
  - Alzira [2 of 2] (volume 3), undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Aroldo (volume 4), undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
    Librettist: Piave, F.M.
    Performance City and Venue: Nobil Teatro di Apollo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1857
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: Tito di Gio. Ricordi
  - Aroldo, 1911 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Attila (volume 5), undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Librettist: Solera, Temistocle
    Performance City and Venue: Fenice: Gran Teatro
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale e Quadragesima 1845-46
    Publication City and Publisher: Venezia: Guiseppe Molinari
  - Attila (volume 6), undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1846-47
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Valentini, E.C.
  - Un Ballo in Maschera (volume 7), 1885 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Librettist: Somma, N.
    Performance City and Venue: Rome: Theatre d'Apollo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1859
    Publication City and Publisher: Paris: Calmann Levy
  - Un Ballo in Maschera (volume 8), undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    Publication City and Publisher: Rome: G. Ricordi and C.
  - La Battaglia di Lengano, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Don Carlo [5 acts] (volume 9), undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    Librettist: du Locle, Mery; du Locle, Camillo
    Performance Season/Date: Stagione 1878-79
  - Don Carlo [4 acts] (volume 10), undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1883-84
  - Ernani, 1863 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Publication City and Publisher: Napoli: unknown
  - Ernani, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    Publication City and Publisher: unknown: Oliver Ditson & Co.
  - Falstaff (volume 14), 1893 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Performance Season/Date: Stagione 1892-93
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: G. Ricordi and C.
  - I due Foscari (volume 11), undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1844-45
  - I due Foscari (volume 12), 1865 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - I due Foscari (volume 13), undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    Performance City and Venue: Pavia: Teatro Condominio
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1865
  - Il finto stanislao, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - La Forza del Destino (volume 15), undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Performance City and Venue: Firenze: R. Teatro della Pergola
    Performance Season/Date: Quaresima 1865
  - La Forza del Destino (volume 16), undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Performance City and Venue: Venezia: Teatro Rossini
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1876
  - Gerusalemme (volume 17), 1850 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Librettist: Royer, Alfonso; Vaez, Gustavo
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1851
  - Un Giorno di Regno (volume 18), 1840 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1840
  - Giovanna d'Arco (volume 19), undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Giovanna d'Arco (volume 20), 1847 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1847
  - Giovanna de Guzman (volume 21), undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    Librettist: Scribe, E.
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Regio
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresimo 1855-56
    Publication City and Publisher: Torino: Guiseppe Fodratti
  - Giovanna de Guzman (volume 22), undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Carlo Felice
    Publication City and Publisher: Genova: Fratelli Pagano
  - Giovanna de Guzman (volume 23), undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    Performance City and Venue: Gram Teatro del Comune
    Performance Season/Date: L'Autunno 1856
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Gio Ricordi
  - Giovanna de Guzman (volume 24), 1857 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1857-58
  - Giovanna de Guzman (volume 25), undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - I Lombardi alla Prima Crociata (volume 26), 1843 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - I Lombardi alla Prima Crociata, 1914 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    Publication City and Publisher: Milan: Casa Editice Madella
  - Luissa Miller, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Macbeth (volume 27), 1847 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    Performance City and Venue: Teatro Civico di Fiume
    Performance Season/Date: Primavera 1852
    Publication City and Publisher: Venice: Rizzi
  - Macbeth (volume 28), undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale 1849
  - Macbeth [nuova edizione] (volume 29), undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    Performance Season/Date: Carnevale-Quaresima 1873-74
  - I Masnadieri (volume 30), umdated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    Librettist: Maffei, Andrea
  - I Masnadieri (volume 31), undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Nabucco (volume 32), 1842 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Nabucco (volume 33), 1842 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    Performance Season/Date: Autunno 1842
  - Nabucco (volume 34), 1842 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Nabucco, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Oberto (volume 35), 1839 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Otello, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)